I'll start off by calculating how many of the pairs of data points are in
سأبدأ بحساب عدد أزواج نقاط البيانات الموجودة في
the same direction relative to their respective means.
نفس الاتجاه المرتبط .بالمتوسطات ذات الصلة
That is, both above the mean or both below the mean.
وهذا بمعنى، أن كلا زوج البيانات فوق المتوسط .أو كليهما دون المتوسط
To do this, I'll first create an array called is_same_direction,
وللقيام بهذا، سأنشئ أولاً ،صفيفًا يُسمى is_same_direction
which contains a boolean for each pair of data points.
يحتوي على عامل منطقي .لكل زوج من نقاط البيانات
Now there are two cases for how the pairs could be in the same direction.
والآن هناك حالتان توضحان .الكيفية التي قد تكون بها أزواج نقاط البيانات في نفس الاتجاه
They could either be both above their means or both below their means.
فقد يكون زوج البيانات فوق المتوسط .أو دون المتوسط
So I'll create two separate arrays of booleans for those two cases.
ولهذا السبب، سأنشئ صفيفين منفصلين .من العوامل المنطقية لهاتين الحالتين
I can use this code to check whether each value of variable1 is
يمكنني استخدام هذه التعليمة البرمجية للتحقق مما إذا كانت كل قيمة للمتغير 1
greater than the mean of variable1, and
أكبر من متوسط المتغير 1، ومما إذا كانت
each value of variable2 is greater than the mean of variable2.
كل قيمة للمتغير 2 أكبر من .متوسط المتغير 2
Again make sure you add the parentheses.
.وأكرر، تأكد من إضافة الأقواس
It's important to do the comparisons first and then do the logical and.
من المهم إجراء المقارنات .أولاً ثم عليك تشغيل and المنطقية
The code to check whether both variables are below the mean is identical
وتتطابق التعليمة البرمجية المستخدمة للتحقق من أن كلا المتغيرين دون المتوسط
except with less than signs instead of greater than signs.
"متطابقين باستثناء احتوائها على علامات "أصغر من ."بدلاً من علامات "أكبر من
Then two variables are in the same direction, if they are both above or
ثم يوجد متغيران في نفس الاتجاه وإذا كانا فوق المتوسط أو دونه
both below their means.
.على حد سواء
Like I mentioned in the instruction video,
وكما ذكرت في ،مقطع الفيديو الخاص بالمدرب
you can add up an array of booleans to see how many of them were true.
يمكنك إضافة صفيف من العوامل المنطقية .لمعرفة عدد الصحيح منها
So I can find the number of pairs that are in the same direction by calculating
ولهذا السبب يمكنني العثور على رقم الزوجين اللذين يكونان في نفس الاتجاه من خلال حساب
is the same direction dot sum.
.is the same direction dot sum
Finally, I can calculate nom different direction by taking the len of variable
وأخيرًا، يمكنني حساب عدد الأزواج المتحركة في اتجاه مختلف من خلال استخلاص الطول (للمتغير 1) مطروحًا منه عدد الأزواج التي تكون في نفس الاتجاه
one minus the number of pairs in the same direction.
.
Last, I'll need to return the two numbers.
وأخيرًا، أحتاج إلى .إرجاع الرقمين
Now if you ran this function for the life expectancy and GDP arrays given in
والآن، إذا قمت بتشغيل هذه الدالة لمتوسط العمر وصفائف GDP المحددة في
the programming exercise, you should have seen that there were 17 pairs that
التمرين على البرمجة، يفترض أنك رأيت أنه كان هناك 17 زوجًا تحركوا
went in the same direction, and three that went in different directions.
في نفس الاتجاه .وثلاثة أزواج تحركوا في اتجاه مختلف
The fact that most of the pairs went in the same direction indicates that these
وتشير حقيقة تحرك معظم الأزواج في نفس الاتجاه إلى أن
two variables are positively correlated.
.هذين المتغيرين مترابطان بشكل إيجابي
That is, when one is higher, the other tends to be higher as well.
أي عندما يكون أحدهما أعلى .يميل الآخر إلى أن يكون أعلى أيضًا
If the first number had been small, and the second number had been large,
،ولو كان العدد الأول صغيرًا ،وكان العدد الثاني كبيرًا
that would indicate that the variables are negatively correlated.
لكان ذلك إشارة إلى أن المتغيرين .مترابطان سلبيًا
When one tends to be large, the other tends to be small.
عندما يميل أحد المتغيرين ليكون كبيرًا .يميل الآخر إلى أن يكون صغيرًا
And if the two numbers had been roughly equal,
ولو كان كلا الرقمين ،متساويين تقريبًا
then that indicates that there might not be a strong relationship.
فقد يكون هذا إشارة إلى .عدم وجود علاقة قوية بينهما
It's about equally likely for
يتعلق الأمر بتساوي احتمال ترابط متغير واحد بشكل إيجابي
one variable to be positively correlated with the other as negatively correlated.
مع ترابط المتغير الآخر .بشكل سلبي